Musawer Ali

Full-Stack Engineer

Father Name: Liaqat Ali

CNIC: 31202-4967789-7

DOB: 21/08/1996

Mailing Address: Pak jali house, Near Shama

Canima Multan Road

Bahawalpur

Email: pakjalihouse@gmail.com

Mobile: +923336513516

Github Profile portfolio

Summary

I'm a highly motivated with 3+ years of experience Full-Stack (**Python/Django/Laravel**) & (**Angular/React/Ionic**) in developing the web application, and have proven to be an asset for my clients. I deliver perfect results , meet deadlines, follow instructions, show daily progress. I always create proper backups and create a dev environment, and use GIT and migration services for any new update. You don't need to micromanage me. And you would not lose any of your valuable data.

I can take ownership, help others, always be learning, and apply my existing skill set to new challenges as we all continue to master the art of software development.

Education

Bachelor of Science, Computer Science

NCBA&E Bahawalpur, Pakistan.

2016-2020

Intermediate, Computer Science

B.I.S.E Bahawalpur Pakistan.

Major: Math, Physic, Computer Science.

2014-2016

Experience

Enigmatix Pvt Ltd.

IT Services and IT Consulting Bahawalpur. <u>Linked-in</u>

Full-Stack(Laravel|Angular|React|Ionic|Django-rest) Developer

Sep 2020 – Jun 2022

- Responsible for web application architecture design and implementations.
- Database analysis and design.
- Payment gateways(Stripe,Payfort).
- Other thirdparty Api's integration.
- Application deployment in AWS, Azure, Heroku.
- Cloud web server configurations.
- Code refactoring, Query and performance Optimization.

Devbatch Pvt Ltd.

IT Services and IT Consulting

Lahore. Linked-in

Angular Developer

Jan 2021 - Aug 2021

• Responsible for bug fixing and implement of new features in Medical apps.

Freelance / Remote

Bahawalpur

PHP Developer Apr 2018-Oct 2020

- Analyzed user requirements and responsible for web application architecture design and implementations.
- Database analysis and design.
- Internal Linux Server setups inside companies.

Portfolio

Hdmapp

About Project:

Its like a social connecting

https://

Roles and Responsibilites

Django/Ionic (ongoing)

- Developing backend in django-rest from scratch.
- Developing frontend in ionic(Capacitor) from scratch.

Private Project

About Project:

Its like a data-sourcing.

https://

Roles and Responsibilites

React

• Implement new features on fronted.

Lighting Stores (Ecommerce)

https://lightingstores.com.sa/ar

Roles and Responsibilites

Laravel

- Integrate Payfort, Stripe, Apple pay.
- Integrate Cashback on products, categories, skus and on fix amount.
- Integrate wallet.
- Order by admin for specific users.
- Bug's fixing.
- Google and Facebook product sync.
- Store products/categories into db from csv file.
- And other functionalities.
- Deployments
- Integrate Shipping methods(DHL,Aramex,Shipox)
- SMS integration (Yamamah)
- Integration Tamara

Build Station (Ecommerce)

https://build-station.com/

Roles and Responsibilites

Laravel

- Integrate Stripe, Apple pay.
- Integrate Cashback on products, categories, skus and on fix amount.
- Integrate wallet.
- Order by admin for specific users.
- Bug's fixing.
- Google and Facebook product sync.
- Store products/categories into db from csv file.
- And other functionalities.
- Deployments
- Integrate Shipping methods(DHL,Aramex,Shipox)
- SMS integration (Yamamah)
- Integration Tamara

Ceramic Home (Ecommerce)

https://ceramichome.com.sa/

Roles and Responsibilites

Laravel

Bug's fixing.

International Medical Center (Health)

https://www.imc.med.sa/en

Roles and Responsibilites

Angular

• Integrate video chat module for doctors and patients in angular by using (twilio,socket.io and flask api) and embed into existing project.

Bug's fixing.
Deployments

Hayaat (Health)
https://hayaat.pk/
Delea and Dean

Roles and Responsibilites

Angular

- Bug's fixing.
- Deployments

Salem (Business Agency)

http://dashboard.salem-sa.com

Roles and Responsibilites

Laravel / React

- Code refactoring in React, Laravel (api's).
- bug fixing.

Robo Theatre (Movies)

https://mymovies.pk/

Roles and Responsibilites

Laravel

- Build from scratch.
- Deploy on linux server.

Jurist (Law guidance)

https://jurist.pk/

Roles and Responsibilites

Laravel

- Build from scratch.
- Deploy on linux server.

MyKamree (Platform for property dealers)

https://jurist.pk/

Roles and Responsibilites

Laravel

- Bug fixing.
- Restructure project (some components).
- Implement new features.

PJH (Business System)

(Inventory system for wholesale Business)

working on local server

Roles and Responsibilites

Laravel / Angular

- Build from scratch.
- Deploy on server.

Skills

- PHP,Laravel
- Python,Django-rest
- Angular,Ionic,React
- API's
- Linux Server's Setups & deployments
- Problem Solving
- Database Design and Analysis
- Git

- Python
- AWS
- Linux, Windows
- DHL, Aramex, Shipox API's
- Payment gateways(Stripe,Payfort)

Extra Activity

- Write Articles on **Medium.**
- Learning AI/ML.
- Try something learn new.